Guide to the Department of Linguistics, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Linguistics, Yale University, records
1963-2000
RU 428
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
The records consist of correspondence, reports, faculty and student records, alumni files, and a paper by Rulon S. Wells entitled "Linguistics at Yale, 1931-1946."
Yale University. Department of Linguistics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, faculty and student records, alumni files, and a paper by Rulon S. Wells entitled "Linguistics at Yale, 1931-1946."
Linguistics -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Wells, Rulon; Yale University. Department of Linguistics
- "Linguistics at Yale, 1931-1946", 1974; Accession 1975-A-005
  - "Linguistics at Yale, 1931-1946," by Rulon S. Wells (Box 1)
- Linguistics Department records, circa 1963-2000; Accession 2008-A-011
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2075
  - Teaching Appointment Forms, 1984-85, 1988-91 (Box 3, Folder 121-123)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1979-91 (Box 3, Folder 124-133)
  - Preliminaries (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Prelim Originals (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Preliminary Exams
    - 1963-77 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 140-142)
    - 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 143-146)
    - 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - 1987 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 150-151)
    - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - 1992 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - 1997 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 157-158)
    - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Comprehensive Exam Questions (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Comprehensive Exams
    - 1963-77 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - 1967-75 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - 1971-79 (Box 3, Folder 164-166)
    - 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Prospectus, pre-1984 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Old Syllabi (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Yale Alumni Forms (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Alumni Fund
    - 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 178-179)
    - 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 181-183)
    - 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 184-186)
    - 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 187-188)
    - 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - 1989-90 (Box 4, Folder 190-191)
  - Indo-European Conference, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 192-193)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1963-71 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - 1968-76 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - 1977-81 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - 1988-89 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - 1989-90 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - 1990-91 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - 1991-92 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - 1992-93 (Box 4, Folder 208-209)
    - 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 210-211)
    - 1994-95 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Donations to Linguistics Library (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - ORBIS (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Library System University (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Connecticut State Library (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - LING Seminar Subscriptions, 1978- (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - LING Sem. Annual Statistics (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Council of the Chairman, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 219-220)
  - Linguistics Dept. Notices
    - 1978-80 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Bulletin, Yale (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - Linguistics Club
    - pre-1986 (Box 4, Folder 227-228)
    - 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - Linguistics Club directions (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Pot Luck Sign-up Sheets (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Ling. Club Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Ling. Club Expense Reports (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Sam Martin Retirement Dinner, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Christmas Party (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Annual Reception, 1989-91 (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Summer Events, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - Morphology + Lexicon Seminar, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - African Linguistics Conference (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - Tzotzil Papers (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - African Studies Council (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Colloquia, 1991-92 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Department Correspondence
    - pre-1980 (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - 1988-89 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Inter-Office Correspondence
    - 1977-82 (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - 1986-88 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Registrar Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - L. Horn Correspondence, 1989-90 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - S. Meiss Correspondence
    - 1982-83 (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - 1983-84 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    - 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Stanley Insler Correspondence
    - 1979-82 (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - 1982-83 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - 1983-84 (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - 1985-86 (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - 1989-90 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Ringe Recommendations, 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Departmental Meetings (Box 5, Folder 263-264)
  - Course Schedules, 1980-84 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Fellowships and Grants, 1976-85 (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Whitney Linguistic Series, pre-1975 (Box 5, Folder 267-269)
  - Comp. Exam Correspondence, 1973-75 (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Course Offerings, 1973-79 (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Appointments, 1968-75 (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - Admissions, 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - Lectures, 1989-91 (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - Miscellaneous, pre-1980 (Box 5, Folder 275-276)